<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>
<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline"></attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="category"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">
           
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
-->

<record>
  <attribute name="headline">ClinEpiDB 3 Released</attribute>
  <attribute name="date">05 Jul 2018 13:00</attribute>
  <attribute name="tag">clinepidb_3_release</attribute>
  <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
  <attribute name="item">
    <![CDATA[
      <div style="font-size:130%"><i>We are pleased to announce the release of ClinEpiDB 3</i></div>
      <section>
        <h4><b>New Features in this Release</b></h4>
        <ul>
        <li>A <a href="https://eupathdb.org/tutorials/ClinEpiDBTutorial3ShinyApp_osh_dh2-2.pdf"><b> new tutorial</b> </a> explains the three analysis apps available in ClinEpiDB after returning search results. These include distributions, contingency tables, and data summarization statistics.
        <li>For each study that will be represented in ClinEpiDB there will be a detailed study data set page. Here you will find information about the study that will be necessary to accurately interpret the data including key details like study design, data collection methodology and a description of the population of interest. For PRISM, in this release we have added data collection materials (Case Report Forms) and data dictionaries.
        </ul>
      </section>
      <section>        <h4><b>No new Data in this Release</b></h4>
      </section>
    ]]>
  </attribute>
</record>


<record>
  <attribute name="headline">ClinEpiDB 2 Released</attribute>
  <attribute name="date">26 Apr 2018 13:00</attribute>
  <attribute name="tag">clinepidb_2_release</attribute>
  <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
  <attribute name="item">
    <![CDATA[
      <div style="font-size:130%"><i>We are pleased to announce the release of ClinEpiDB 2</i></div>
      <section>
        <h4><b>New Features in this Release</b></h4>
        <ul>
        <li>A <a href="https://eupathdb.org/tutorials/ClinEpiDBTutorial2ResultstableanddownloadsFINAL.pdf"><b> new tutorial</b> </a> explains the options ClinEpiDB provides to explore results after performing a search. These include the dynamic tabular outputs, column visualization tools, and data download options.
        <li>In the Distributions app we have added automatically generated summary statistics: mean, median, range, SD (standard deviation) & interquartile range (IQR)
        <li>Improvements to our axis labels in our analysis apps
        <li>Implementation of indicators of available data. Filters are now annotated with eg. 1 of 44,508 Observations have no data provided for this filter.
        <li>Improvements to Active Filters summary popup describing more clearly filter selections, especially in the Related Observations step.
        </ul>
      </section>
      <section>        <h4><b>No new Data in this Release</b></h4>
      </section>
    ]]>
  </attribute>
</record>

<record>
  <attribute name="headline">ClinEpiDB 1 Released</attribute>
  <attribute name="date">16 Feb 2018 13:00</attribute>
  <attribute name="tag">clinepidb_1_release</attribute>
  <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
  <attribute name="item">
    <![CDATA[
      <div style="font-size:130%"><i>We are pleased to announce the first release of ClinEpiDB</i></div>
      <section>
        <h3><b>This release of ClinEpiDB contains data from the Program for Resistance, Immunology, Surveillance and Modeling of Malaria in Uganda (PRISM) study. PRISM is the dedicated East Africa International Center of Excellence for Malaria Research. The data presented here include the longitudinal cohort and entomological surveillance components of the <a href="/ce/app/record/dataset/DS_0ad509829e">PRISM study</a>.</b></h3>
      </section>
      <section>
        <h4><b>New Features in this Release</b></h4>
        <ul>
        <li>The contingency table app allows you to create 2x2 contingency tables of different categorical variables or allows you to create categorical variables from continuous measurements. Here you can explore the relationship between two variables.
        <li>The data summary app for longitudinal datasets, allows you to plot summary information, similar to a box-and-whisker plot for variables over time. The timeline(s) allow you to filter by time periods and age groups of interest.
        <li>The Distributions app allows you to visualize histograms of available variables and then facet or stratify these distributions by additional variablaes.
        </ul>
      </section>
      <section>
        <aside>
        </aside>
      </section>
    ]]>
  </attribute>
</record>


 
</xmlAnswer>

